Welcome to the world of your dreams!
Absolute Beginners is a drama, music, romance film directed by Julien Temple.
A musical adaptation of Colin MacInnes' novel about life in late 1950s London.
Nineteen-year-old photographer Colin is hopelessly in love with model Crepe Suzette, but her
relationships are strictly connected with her progress in the fashion world.
So Colin gets involved with a pop promoter and tries to crack the big time.
Meanwhile, racial tension is brewing in Colin's Notting Hill housing estate...
Colin, Photographer / Narrator, played by Eddie O'Connell.
Suzette, played by Patsy Kensit.
Henley of Mayfair, Dressmaker to the Queen, played by James Fox.
Vendice Partners, played by David Bowie.
Arthur, Colin's Dad, played by Ray Davies.
Flora, Colin's Mum, played by Mandy Rice-Davies.
Absolute Beginners is a 1986 British musical film adapted from Colin MacInnes'
book about life in late 1950s London, directed by Julien Temple.
The film stars Eddie O' Connell, Patsy Kensit, James Fox, Edward Tudor-Pole, Anita Morris, and
David Bowie, with featured appearances by Sade Adu, Ray Davies, and Steven Berkoff.
It was screened out of competition at the 1986 Cannes Film Festival.
It received coverage in the British media but was panned by critics and became a box
office failure, although modern reviews have been more favourable.
Bowie's theme song was very popular in the UK, spending nine
weeks on the charts and peaking at number two.
The commercial failure of Absolute Beginners and two other films is blamed for the collapse of
British film studio Goldcrest Films and for Virgin Films withdrawing from production.
The film explores themes of london, england,
photographer, musical, modeling, 1950s.
The tone is emotional.